THUONG MAI

• thuongmai10292@gmail.com

• https://github.com/thuongmai • https://www.linkedin.com/in/thuong-mai/

Software Developer/Front End Developer

Skills Profile/ Highlights

Developer with 5 years of experience in learning and developing software applications, with 1 year of working in fast-paced environments. Successfully completed three coop work terms at NAV Canada and Mobile Innovations. A programmer committed to providing high quality and efficient code using Object Oriented Design and Software Design Patterns. Highly interested in solving code challenges, doing complex projects, and eager to learn and utilize new technologies

Technical Skills

- Proficient in Java, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript and AJAX
- Experience in graphics design through gaming projects and knowledge of wireframing
- Understanding of C#, .NET framework and ASP.NET though co-op work with Mobile Innovations company
- Strong experience in SQL and other relational database architectures
- Experience in creating test cases, documenting code to build functionally-robust code
- Experience in source control (Git, SVN), Agile software development methodology (Scrum), software development life cycle, algorithms, and data structures

Soft Skills

- Strong communication and writing skills, interact with clients and students through jobs
- Experience in working both independently and collaborate with other team members
- Strong analytical, evaluative and problem-solving skills through years of training
- Effectively work on multiple tasks with different programming languages and systems

Education

Bachelor of Computer Science. Minor in mathematics

Sep 2012 - Aug 2018

Carleton University, Ottawa, Ontario, Canada

6 years

High Achievers Entrance Scholarship

Work Experience

Teaching Assistant

Sep 2017 - Dec 2017

Carleton University, Ottawa, Ontario, Canada

4 months

- Marked 5 assignments and midterm of up to 50 students each independently
- Assisted students through forum and emails in understanding the course materials

Mobile Developer - Coop (Xamarin, Android, C# .NET, SQL)

May 2016 - Aug 2016

Mobile Innovations, Ottawa, Ontario, Canada

4 months

- Developed the cross-platform mobile app that helps law enforcement personnel do their work faster by connecting to SQL database server
- Created, updated and tested new user feature development and user interfaces
- Debugged and tested the software on multiple mobile platforms (Android, Blackberry, iOS) to ensure that the application was displaying and running correctly
- Modified the NSIS installer's source code to guide users in setting up compatible .Net framework and app on Windows

Software Developer - Coop (Java EE, PostgreSQL, MVC, Git)

Sep 2014 – Apr 2015

NAV CANADA, Ottawa, Ontario, Canada

8 months

- Worked independently in developing the Java application for users to retrieve, filter, and sort data
- Analyzed users' requirements and provided solution to modify the application, design new user interfaces and troubleshoot problems
- Improved the loading time of the application from 30 minutes to 5 seconds when retrieving data from the server
- Received positive feedback from the customers due to its fast loading database time, resulting a second coop work term with the company

Applied Projects

Network-based Multiplayer Card Game (Java, Spring, Networking) Jan 2018 – Apr 2018

- Collaborated with other students to create a 2D multiplayer networking card game
- Designed the game framework, GUI and implemented Artificial Intelligence (AI) and the logic of the game
- The game can be played by 2-4 players online through local host

Password System – Quantitative Usability (Java)

Jan 2018 - Apr 2018

- Surveyed a group of Carleton University students using regular text-based password system to understand the problem and analyze the recalling time
- Researched, designed and implemented new password scheme to help users recall password faster while maintaining security and private
- Documented new concepts and research on how the new password system better

Web Application – (JavaScript, React JS, SQL)

Jan 2017 - Apr 2017

- Created a cross-platform application using React JS in designing user interfaces
- Implemented the back-end database using Microsoft SQL server express
- The application could run on the web and connected to the server

Resource Management Widget – Operating System (C++)

Jan 2017 - Apr 2017

- Created a tool to monitor real-time consumption of resources in Linux system
- Designed a Graphical User Interface (GUI) using Qt (C++) to provide a lightweight, compact tool as a widget to keep track of the resources on real time

Ride of the Valkyries – third person 3D game (C++)

Sep 2016 – Dec 2016

- Worked in a team of 3 to create a 3D battle helicopter game that shoots and survives against the waves of enemies
- Used C++ and Orge3D graphics rendering engine

Grease Monkey – 2D arcade game (C++)

Jan 2016 – Apr 2016

- Worked in a team of 3 to create a 2D arcade, racing, strategy game that controls a vehicle to collect power items and avoid being hit by Artificial Intelligence (AI) enemies
- Used C++ with SFML library to design the game

Ball Drop - 2D arcade game (Java)

Jan 2013 – Apr 2013

- Worked in a team of 2 to create a unique game with colorful graphic, gameplay and physics collision using Processing/Java and math (vector, geometry, trigonometric)
- Managed time effectively, received the mark of 104.5% on the project and was archived in Carleton University Library for reference